individually as one user I want to be
able to decide what bread I want and
when I want it
how many lobes I want so that is an
individual choice as a group we can
decide on how to efficiently get that
done how to create a bakery that gets me
my salary dough use your pumpernickel
you your rye and all of the above for a
family of 20 who likes it all creating
the bakery from scratch and having to be
in competition with everybody else is
what currently exists so you don't just
make pumpernickel for yourself you
figure out how to make it for the five
of you and enough people to make that
efficient but you're in competition with
everyone else which makes it not
efficient getting ten thousand people
together to say how do we make our get
our 10,000 families breads needs made
that's doable and how do we bring that
cost down how do we share in that labor
how do we both buy ingredients to make
it cheaper at a local level we do that
we figure out how many of us need a
bakery then we create the bakery we bake
the bread locally because breads better
locally we make the decisions on what
the packaging is it is efficient how we
get it to us the user is it delivered
this woman leave him with all the trucks
and going delivering each individual
bread that sounds like not a great
option but when we also solve it for
vegetables and eggs and milk and
together we get it delivered that sounds
like a great option
so there's then regionally regionally we
want to be able to bulk buy ingredients
with not just our bakery but other
bakeries we want to be able to start a
niche bakery well turns out not everyone
wants pumpernickel rye or sourdough some
people are gluten-free
are there enough gluten-free people to
have a local bakery that's gluten free
and have it be cheap maybe not what
about a larger region how many how big
of a region do we need to have that
10,000 people so there's things that
make sense to do regionally probably
milling it until we get to the point
where we have a local
Mills in our bakeries they grind it
fresh so that it maintains its its
nutritional value but we can decide on
that right does it make sense to mill
ourselves we can decide globally what
makes sense well the machines in the
bakeries don't make sense for us to have
locally or regionally we don't all need
a we all need bread we need it to be
baked in ovens we don't need an oven
making factory in every town the parts
that go into those machines as well as
the other thing that's done on a global
scale is the technology that goes into
running the bakery to managing the
inventory to managing the labor to have
the feedback system to know how much
bread should we be baking feeds back
from the customer themselves saying
here's what the bread I want they
themselves don't want to have an app
just to order bread they want an app to
order all of their groceries which goes
to the individual makers and gets
compiled into one one delivery and then
given to you I don't want to have to
wait by the door for every every loaf of
bread everything of eggs everything of
milk I want to deliver to me I don't
want it to feed back into the system my
individual needs so that it knows guess
what you get a thing of milk every week
here you go
you get bread every so in this often it
goes mouldy maybe you need half a loaf
of bread your neighbor also likes bread
and also the same thing happens we're
gonna give you each half a loaf if you
would like if you want to hold off and
you want it to be thrown out moldy every
week by all means power to you
the technology is can be global and it
can help you as an individual have more
autonomy on your choices as well as how
to collectively work together to have a
gluten-free Bakery to have a peanut free
bakery get your allergy needs met or
your taste needs met you have a weird
choice like it's your favorite loaf of
bread but no one else likes it maybe we
can make it for you one day a year you
can come in and use the equipment and
make it yourself and store it in the
freezer if that's a fee if that's a
feasible thing to do together we can
share an innovation and recipes on our
technology
nothing is mandatory you don't have to
share your innovation with everybody you
don't have to share your grandmother's
recipe with everyone but if everybody
else is innovating and you have a new
way to innovate to shave off two seconds
the next person's innovation is going to
shave off another two seconds in another
second and so we're all going to be able
to benefit off of sharing that
innovation if we all have the recipes
available then we can say which one we
want locally and and make those ones
make the ones that work for the most
people but then the nice bread can get
made more regionally and create the
technology that makes it efficient
without ever demanding the individual
view up their autonomy and empowering
the group to make decisions together and
giving them the technology to make that
feasible that has the feedback systems
that less stuff is going to waste
we're getting more bread out of less
labor we're getting a delivery system
that doesn't just work for bread it
works for everything we're getting when
there's an innovation on we don't want
it in paper because it doesn't keep it
fresh and we don't want it in plastic
because plastic is bad for the
environment oh you have a solution you
came up with a hemp bag that we can just
put it in there how fast can you make
those have bags we as a region we as a
bakery can say yes we want to use yours
and we want other people to use yours
too because its solution that helps the
planet when innovation happens you
already have your customers ready to go
just like we want to use your handbag
thank you instead of needing to fight in
the competitive marketplace to find the
people who might want it fighting
against customers who are like hemp bag
that's weird
because we're certain bulbs in the
decision-making process and you don't
have to be any more involved in the
decision making process than you have to
be you can use the bakery without having
to attend bakery meetings but then
you're giving up your right to be part
of those bakery meetings we can have it
be regional we can have it be grassroots
and have the global efficiency because
we're competing already on a global
scale we're competing with Google we're
competing with Facebook we can
out-compete them by using
our innovation together by coming
together and creating what makes sense
to be cooperative and without giving up
our personal autonomy hope that
showcased it a bit with the bakery
analogy
I'm not even analogy let's do that I
would really like my bread to be made
locally and fresh and have it not be
seven bucks a loaf that I have to stand
in line for it just hurts my door that
sounds awesome
I want more better food now but it's not
happening though we're creating the
technology not the bakeries so please
like and subscribe and I'll see you
tomorrow